Ashley Jaynes

Software Engineer I

Seattle, WA 98112

ashley.jaynes@mac.com

Front-end developer with over 10 years' experience managing and overseeing the development of a variety of digital products. Adept at creating new best practices and procedures to expedite production time and raise quality while reducing expenses. Can juggle multiple projects, lead and mentor team members, and provide training and documentation for all departmental products while meeting tight deadlines.

Work Experience

Senior Developer

Overdose.

June 2021 to Present

- Engineered dozens of solutions for complex business problems
- Developed an inventory grid that allows wholesale customers to see future shipping/production dates for products.
- Built a React customer account application for customers to view their orders, invoices, and account balances
- Created multiple node scripts for importing and modifying thousands of products.
- Authored code review and deployment process
- Mentored junior developers

Senior Developer

Mercutio

August 2019 to June 2021

- Engineered dozens of solutions for complex business problems
- Developed an inventory grid that allows wholesale customers to see future shipping/production dates for products.
- Built a React customer account application for customers to view their orders, invoices, and account balances.
- Created multiple node scripts for importing and modifying thousands of products.
- Authored code review and deployment process
- Mentored junior developers

Software Engineer I

Ascent Services Group

February 2019 to June 2019

- Developed dozens of reusable, modular designs for a proprietary CMS.
- Authored dozens of repository READMEs
- Reviewed pull requests
- Validated release updates in production and live environments
- Implemented code changes and updates to remove tech debt from repositories

Senior Web Developer & UX Specialist

Dauntless Inc.

May 2018 to February 2019

- Built internal and external web applications that reduced the workload for the development team.
- Led the development team in prototyping and wireframing assorted web applications.
- Designed user interfaces for various pieces of software, both web and executables.
- Collaborated with the executive team to devise the scope and roadmap of development for the company's largest product to date.
- Produced user stories and flows for an assortment of software applications.

Web Project Manager

SmartLok Systems Inc June 2017 to April 2018

- Implemented, administered, and provided training and documentation for Jira
- Designed and wrote all technical documents for SmartLok products
- Designed and developed user interface for SmartLok software

Freelance, Front End Developer

August 2016 to June 2017

- Designed and developed new websites
- Created new user interfaces
- Optimized WordPress sites for speed and SEO

Lead Web Developer

Big Tex Trailers Mfg

October 2012 to August 2016

- Established the process for rapid website development and deployment
- Led a team of three web developers ensuring projects were completed on time, on budget, and met quality standards
- Formulated the web department's QA process
- Introduced a ticketing system for our external and internal clients to allow our team to answer requests more efficiently
- Authored documentation on all procedures for the web department
- Implemented Git on all projects so the whole web team could collaborate more easily

Web Designer/Front End Developer

MarketVex

November 2010 to October 2012

- Designed and developed new websites
- Created new user interfaces
- Optimized WordPress sites for speed and SEO

Web Designer/Web Developer

Wolfnet Technologies

January 2010 to November 2010

• Assisted managers, developers, and analysts in the conceptualization and development of web interfaces

- · Worked with software developers in integration of web interfaces with server-side code
- Assisted in the preparation and documentation of program requirements and specifications

Web Designer

Ackmann & Dickenson September 2009 to January 2010

- Integrated existing static sites into Content Management Systems
- Created web graphics and other marketing materials
- Tested cross-browser and cross-platform compatibility of designs

Media, Lead Web Designer

UnityWorks

January 2008 to September 2009

- Led group of 4 web designers, ensuring accuracy and timely project completion
- Reduced the turnaround time for project completion from 5 business days to 2 business days.
- Developed a Best Practice for setting up bulk social networking for hundreds of clients
- Developed Best Practices to streamline graphic production and minimize errors

Education

B.S. in Digital Media & Design

Arkansas State University

2002 to 2007

Skills

- Git
- Javascript
- Reactis
- Svn
- Ui
- CSS
- REST
- Agile
- Bootstrap
- GitHub
- HTML5

Links

http://www.ashleyjaynes.com

http://www.github.com/ajaynes

http://www.linkedin.com/in/ashleyjaynes

Additional Information

Skills & Abilities

Leadership, Mentoring, Problem-solving, Collaborating, Team Building, JavaScript, ReactJS, HTML5, CSS3, SASS/LESS, Git/SVN, Adobe Creative Suite, WordPress, SEO, UI/UX Design